<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Bits of Insight</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Bits of Insight</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 07:02:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Move Linux b/w Drives</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_hdd_nvme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_hdd_nvme/</guid><description>Flash memories comes in different forms and use different interfaces to connect. Pen drives use flash memory while SSDs use solid state storage. SSDs can be interfaced with your mobo1 either through SATA or PCIe; M.2 is actually a form factor (standard stating about the size and form of such drives which are small and rectangular; looks like RAM modules compared to the 2.5 inch drives), connecting to your mobo via PCIe with the logical interface options of AHCI (legacy) or NVMe.</description></item><item><title>Resize root under LVM</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/lvm_resize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 07:36:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/lvm_resize/</guid><description>My root partition had unused space while /home was starving. I needed to resize both without data loss. I’d foreseen this and created my Linux partitions using LVM while installing Arch 😇 .
Since operations here involve resizing /, boot from Live USB and then perform them. Also make sure the USB is UEFI bootable; otherwise it’d mean changing BIOS settings to enable Legacy Boot. This may lead to GRUB’s disappearance from boot menu.</description></item><item><title>GRUB Recovery</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/grub2_recovery/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:35:20 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/grub2_recovery/</guid><description>I tried upgrading the firmware of my old iOmega 1 TB HDD. Internally it’s a Barracuda LP family, ST31000520AS model Segate HDD. Seagate had released a firmware upgrade for this drive in 2010. I’m around 9 years late to the party!
My laptop doesn’t have a CD-ROM drive, also I prefer burning the ISO to a USB stick &amp;mdash; why waste a CD, eh? Rufus kindly refused as the supplied Seagate update ISO’s boot format was unrecognizable.</description></item><item><title>Arch Linux Configuration</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_config/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 11:31:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_config/</guid><description>See Arch Linux Installation for installation notes.
Network In the newly installed Arch you might notice that there&amp;rsquo;s no network connectivity.
Wireless To enable wireless do what you did during installation (see Arch Linux Installation, §2 Wireless Network). I did it only to realize, for netctl to hook to a WPA-secured network, the wpa_supplicant package is needed but was absent on the installed system. To connect to the internet, you need a package from the internet!</description></item><item><title>Arch Linux Installation</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_install/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 17:00:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_install/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve a dual GPU laptop: Lenovo Legion Y520-15IKBN; the Nvidia GeForce 1050 Ti Mobile for graphics-heavy (3D) tasks and Intel HD Graphics 630 for rendering the rest. It has an SSD and a traditional spinning disk. UEFI + GPT as opposed to the classic BIOS + MBR combo is preferable. I&amp;rsquo;m a long-time Xubuntu user but I wanted to try Arch Linux. Here I note my experience in getting this laptop up and running.</description></item></channel></rss>