<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Bits of Insight</title>
    <link>https://legends2k.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Bits of Insight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:35:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GRUB Recovery</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/grub2_recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:35:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/grub2_recovery/</guid>
      <description>I tried upgrading the firmware of my old iOmega 1 TB HDD. Internally it’s a Barracuda LP family, ST31000520AS model Segate HDD. Seagate had released a firmware upgrade for this drive in 2010. I’m around 9 years late to the party!
My laptop doesn’t have a CD-ROM drive, also I prefer burning the ISO to a USB stick &amp;mdash; why waste a CD, eh? Rufus kindly refused as the supplied Seagate update ISO’s boot format was unrecognizable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Configuration</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_config/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 17:00:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_config/</guid>
      <description>See Arch Linux Installation for installation notes.
Network In the newly installed Arch you might notice that there&#39;s no network connectivity. To enable do what you did during installation (see Arch Linux Installation, §2 Wireless Network). I did it only to realize, for netctl to hook to a WPA-secured network, the wpa_supplicant package is needed but was absent on the installed system. To connect to the internet, you need a package from the internet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Linux Installation</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_install/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 17:00:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/arch_install/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve a dual GPU laptop: Lenovo Legion Y520-15IKBN; the Nvidia GeForce 1050 Ti Mobile for graphics-heavy (3D) tasks and Intel HD Graphics 630 for rendering the rest. It has an SSD and a traditional spinning disk. UEFI + GPT as opposed to the classic BIOS + MBR combo is preferable. I&#39;m a long-time Xubuntu user but I wanted to try Arch Linux. Here I note my experience in getting this laptop up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>