<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hardware on Bits of Insight</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in Hardware on Bits of Insight</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 14:02:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raspberry Pi 4 Setup</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/rpi4_setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 11:27:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/rpi4_setup/</guid><description>I neither have a micro HDMI adapter nor a dedicated display for the Pi. I just want to use it as a server. Thanks to Raspbian for providing a simple way to auto-enable SSH on boot!
I prefer the leaner, manual approach over NOOBS, the more popular option.
dd Raspbian’s image on to a new SD card To auto-start SSH service on boot touch ssh in /boot partition Insert SD card, connect ethernet cable (RJ-45) and boot Check IP address assigned to RPi from your router’s portal ssh -l pi IP Change default password (raspberry) with passwd sudo apt update sudo apt upgrade Use raspi-config and setup Locale Wi-Fi country code Needed to abide by your country’s wireless laws Radio device may not work properly if not done Wi-Fi (SSID and password) Enable SSH (for good measure) Check systemctl is-enabled sshd Make sure wireless isn’t soft-blocked: rfkill list and rfkill unblock wifi Unplug ethernet and wireless should work now Use ifconfig to know your Mac address eth0/wlan0 interfaces that’re up have inet (IP address) populated Use raspi-config and enable VNC Setup VNC password: sudo vncpasswd -service Boot into Desktop instead of Console in System Options -&amp;gt; Boot / Auto Login See this if you want to boot to CLI and startx later [3] Make sure to select a resolution under Display Options -&amp;gt; Resolution For macOS Screen Sharing to work, make /etc/vnc/config.</description></item><item><title>Shutting the ubiquitous backdoor</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/clean_me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 15:00:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/clean_me/</guid><description>I believe resistance is futile if someone is bent on spying on you; there’re both serious and creative ways to go about it. Talking to your processor, behind your back, isn’t the primary or only means. Our’s is a golden age where corporates and government agencies stoop low enough to pry into bedrooms. Did you know that almost all machines1 you own have a processor aside from the one you paid for?</description></item><item><title>Drawing tablet setup on Windows</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/tablet_setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 10:53:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/tablet_setup/</guid><description>Steps Disable Windows defaults Windows 10 Run → services.msc → Touch Keyboard and Handwriting Panel Service; stop and disable Disable Tablet mode under Tablet mode settings Windows 7 Disable Tablet PC services from the Windows Features list Disable Flicks in Pen and Tablet settings Install latest manufacturer drivers before first plugging in to the system Plug in device and test Enable Force Proportions to avoid disproportionate lines Tablet Area: Full Screen Area: Monitor Force Proportions mightn&amp;rsquo;t be available on non-Wacom driver software like Huion&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item></channel></rss>