<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits of Insight</title>
    <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bits of Insight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:14:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Being Slow</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/on_being_slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 12:52:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/on_being_slow/</guid>
      <description>A colleague asked an intriguing question: &amp;ldquo;what kinda processor are you?&amp;rdquo;. He explained me the classification:
Internal Processor: A person who gives one clear statement after having formulated what to say (including corrections, refinements, etc.) internally External Processor: A person who says something and then goes on making a string of corrections until satisfied &amp;ndash; externally My reply? &amp;ldquo;I’m an internal processor&amp;hellip; Oh! Wait! I think&amp;hellip; Oh well!&amp;rdquo;. Colleague walks away with a knowing grin 😀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sell Yourself Short</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/galls_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 13:10:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/galls_law/</guid>
      <description>People often start a new endeavour to realise a vivid dream. This is good by itself; the dream coupled with strong self-motivation would take them far when the going gets tough (which it usually does).
However, there’s another side to dreams that’s dreadful, particularly for someone starting something new1 and with little experience.
Unrealistic Expectations It’s no secret; when learning your work won’t be original, beautiful or fulfilling. Experience shows us that anyone’s first picture is not far from a scribble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideating vs Acting</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/ideating_acting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 23:23:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/ideating_acting/</guid>
      <description>Ideas Young people are constantly bombarded with free advice by the elderly: people tell them how to talk, how to socialize, how to deal with money matters, etc. It’s done to the point where it’s felt as preachy and rightly so. Why? More than what you say, kids pick up what you do. Words don’t mean much to them; actions speak much louder indeed.
Even as adults we read motivational text, watch TED talks, discuss problems with friends and get ideas/free advice all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in the Valley</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/valley_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 10:35:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/valley_review/</guid>
      <description>I lived in Silicon Valley for over a year (2016-18). Like all humans I developed opinions about my new environment; I want to record them under notes-to-self. Before proceeding, I&amp;rsquo;ll lay down the disclaimer: these are just my views and you&amp;rsquo;re totally entitled to your&amp;rsquo;s. Though I try to be reasonable, absolute logic isn&amp;rsquo;t just impractical but is inapplicable since feelings about one&amp;rsquo;s environment are always rooted in emotions, upbringing, habit, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Inspirers</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:41:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</guid>
      <description>I have been inspired by many unknown personalities all over the internet and otherwise, but a few linger on my mind consistently to be listed here. Not all of them are authors but their works inspired me in some way.
Kalki R. Krishnamurthy A great writer, and freedom fighter, who effortlessly balanced content against gripping narration. He pioneered in writing under a unique genre &amp;mdash; Historical Fiction &amp;mdash; by mixing imagination with facts in the right amount and proved that it can be done with great success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello, world</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:36:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Experience I have been writing on StackOverflow for quite a while now. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if these can be called writing since it&amp;rsquo;s purely technical. However, helping newbies with verbose answers has stoked some confidence in me; confidence that I am good at explaining things to people. Additionally, I recently gave an interactive presentation on a math-heavy topic that garnered good reviews; it took 2 months for me to prepare this slide deck viewable on a browser; more than half the time was spent not on technicalities but on the material.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
