<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits of Insight on CGrok</title>
    <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bits of Insight on CGrok</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:14:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Inspirers</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:41:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been inspired by many unknown personalities all over the internet and otherwise, but a few linger on my mind consistently to be listed here.  Not all of them are authors but they work inspired me in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kalki-r-krishnamurthy&#34;&gt;Kalki R. Krishnamurthy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kalki_Krishnamurthy&#34;&gt;A &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; writer&lt;/a&gt;, and freedom fighter, who effortlessly balanced content against gripping narration.  He pioneered in writing under a unique genre &amp;mdash; Historical fiction &amp;mdash; by mixing imagination with facts in the right amount and proved that it can be done with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ponniyin_Selvan&#34;&gt;great success&lt;/a&gt;.  He&amp;rsquo;s the only author I have seen to give evidences in a fictional work.  Though &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamil_language&#34;&gt;Tamil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is my mother tongue, I am sure I am unbiased here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;joel-spolsky&#34;&gt;Joel Spolsky&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Witty, provoking and insightful writer of technical topics.  I like many of his articles, but these come up readily:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2006/08/01/can-your-programming-language-do-this/&#34;&gt;Can your programming language do this?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2005/12/29/the-perils-of-javaschools-2/&#34;&gt;Perils of Java Schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2002/11/11/the-law-of-leaky-abstractions/&#34;&gt;The Law of Leaky Abstractions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/2001/10/14/in-defense-of-not-invented-here-syndrome/&#34;&gt;In Defense of Not-Invented-Here Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;eris-s-raymond&#34;&gt;Eris S. Raymond&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacker, writer who defined the defining characteristics of a hacker.  If you are a programmer, or are aspiring to becoming a good one, I strongly recommend you know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/smart-questions.html&#34;&gt;How To Ask Questions The Smart Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html&#34;&gt;How To Become A Hacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dennis-m-ritchie&#34;&gt;Dennis M. Ritchie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s creator of the &lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; programming language, co-author of &lt;em&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/em&gt; and the poster child for the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_philosophy&#34;&gt;Unix Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; it shows in his language design.  His writings are, to me, the canonical example of clear, concise technical content.  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bell-labs.com/usr/dmr/www/hist.html&#34;&gt;The Evolution of the Unix Time-sharing system&lt;/a&gt;, do so to see how pipes came into computers and why coroutines are cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kalil-azad&#34;&gt;Kalil Azad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://betterexplained.com/&#34;&gt;BetterExplained.com&lt;/a&gt;.  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been to this excellent site, head there &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;!  You&amp;rsquo;ll be wondering why your teachers weren&amp;rsquo;t this good.  Recommended reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://betterexplained.com/articles/learning-how-to-count-avoiding-the-fencepost-problem/&#34;&gt;Avoiding The Fencepost Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://betterexplained.com/articles/a-gentle-introduction-to-learning-calculus/&#34;&gt;A Gentle Introduction To Learning Calculus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://betterexplained.com/articles/why-do-we-learn-math/&#34;&gt;Why Do We Learn Math?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scott-h-young&#34;&gt;Scott H. Young&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This man successfully completed MIT’s 4-year undergraduate computer science curriculum in 12 months, &lt;em&gt;without taking any classes&lt;/em&gt;.  He also propagandised the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scotthyoung.com/learnonsteroids/grab/TranscriptFeynman.pdf&#34;&gt;Feynman technique&lt;/a&gt; you may use to learn any topic in any domain.  He has written many great articles of which &lt;a href=&#34;https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world#writing-a-powerful-tool&#34;&gt;one stands out&lt;/a&gt; as an inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;richard-feynman&#34;&gt;Richard Feynman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He needs no introduction.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feynmanlectures.info/&#34;&gt;His essays on Physics&lt;/a&gt; are the go-to literature if you are an amateur physicist.  He devised the Feynman technique for learners venturing into new fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;carl-sagan&#34;&gt;Carl Sagan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An astronomer behind the SETI project.  I like him more for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos:_A_Personal_Voyage&#34;&gt;Cosmos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; I could really appriciate the cause he was calmly fighting for in it; it&amp;rsquo;s relevent even now that there&amp;rsquo;re re-makes of it.  I always fall for his &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pale_Blue_Dot&#34;&gt;Pale Blue Dot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;; makes me realise how insignificant humans are in the grand scheme of things and reminds me to make good use of the limited time I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jerry-seinfeld&#34;&gt;Jerry Seinfeld&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big fan of his comedies, but as a creator, he freely shares his secret recipe: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;The Seinfeld Technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.  I have benefited from this technique more than once to develop better habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;daniel-kahneman&#34;&gt;Daniel Kahneman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was dumb struck when I watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_kahneman_the_riddle_of_experience_vs_memory&#34;&gt;his Ted talk&lt;/a&gt; that explains the experiencing self and the remembering self.  I came to know its implications later when I started mediating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-more&#34;&gt;And more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People like &lt;em&gt;Salman Khan&lt;/em&gt;, the educator, &lt;em&gt;Amit Patel&lt;/em&gt;, whose blog is a treasure trove of interactive articles for a game developer, and numerous other open source developers like &lt;em&gt;Richard M Stallman&lt;/em&gt;,  &lt;em&gt;Linus Torvalds&lt;/em&gt;, who open up their work for the betterment of humanity and respect freedom are my inspirations too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello, world</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:36:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been writing on &lt;em&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/em&gt; for quite a while now.  I don&amp;rsquo;t know if these can be called writing since it&amp;rsquo;s purely technical.  However, &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/users/183120/legends2k&#34;&gt;helping newbies with verbose answers&lt;/a&gt; has stoked some confidence in me; confidence that I am good at explaining things to people.  Additionally, I recently gave an &lt;a href=&#34;http://legends2k.github.io/2d-transforms-101&#34;&gt;interactive presentation on a math-heavy topic&lt;/a&gt; that garnered good reviews; it took 2 months for me to prepare this slide deck viewable on a browser; more than half the time was spent &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; on technicalities but on the material.  This also gave me a taste for good, clear explanations and I dare say, good writing in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;search-for-intuition&#34;&gt;Search for Intuition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a patron of &lt;a href=&#34;http://betterexplained.com/&#34;&gt;Better Explained&lt;/a&gt;; a site that explains technical concepts, like Calculus, Physics, in a way that builds intuition.  I share a belief with its creator, Kalid Azad: &lt;strong&gt;technical topics are tagged thus only because they are presented in a bad fashion to freshers&lt;/strong&gt;.  Oodles of symbol vomit and no fun would naturally steer a fresher away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every master was once a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remembering this fact, building intuition should be the prime effort of teachers; for once the learner is hooked, delving into the details (rigour) would naturally follow.  So I belong to the camp that says &amp;ldquo;sacrificing rigour for intuition is OK.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention is to not just write.  I believe mere words aren&amp;rsquo;t enough to get the idea through; figures and interactive content are essential.  No wonder many books are dubbed &lt;em&gt;boring&lt;/em&gt; in this day and age where content can be a lot richer, spanning beyond words and symbols.  I believe well-written books still have their place when one wants to study a subject in depth; &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/q/25094299/#comment39048388_25094363&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve often recommended it&lt;/a&gt;; but they can be enthusiasm-killers for a newbie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;writing-a-powerful-tool&#34;&gt;Writing &amp;ndash; a powerful tool&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers#scott-h-young&#34;&gt;Scott H. Young&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2006/02/24/writing-to-solve-personal-problems/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writing to Solve Personal Problems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; begins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incredibly powerful technique for solving problems is by simply writing it down. It seems rather simple, but it can often allow you to solve problems you previously thought were impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It left a strong impression on me.  I&amp;rsquo;ve done this unconscionably many times but when he put it out there like that, it solidified in my mind.  I realised how powerful a tool writing is.  Another reason why writing things down is a good thing: it helps others and oneself become conscious of habits and traits ingrained within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;learner-writer&#34;&gt;Learner ➰ Writer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a depth-oriented guy.  I keep exploring various topics &amp;mdash; programming, math, science &amp;mdash; and I find it hard to build intuition.  I take my time in understanding various pieces of a topic until they all fall in place in my head; the penny &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; drops.  Once internalised, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/rmsundaram/tryouts&#34;&gt;I write code&lt;/a&gt; to concretise my comprehension of the concept; most of the math I intuitively understand is because of the code I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I embellish code generously with comments to make sure my future self recall&amp;rsquo;s what I grokked.  As I kept writing these comments I realised something deeper: just the act of writing comments, with the intention of explaining it, not to just myself, but for any future reader in general, made my understanding lucid by filling the holes in my mental model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I find it selfish to leave the bread crumbs in comments.  How many people read code to understand something?  How can the aforementioned interactive learning tools be put in comments?  This is a place where I try to explain things that occurred to me in hopes that its readers share my joy of understanding something intuitively.  I hope to give life to words with figures and interactive demos along the way.  Instead of complaining about someone&amp;rsquo;s writing, griping I couldn&amp;rsquo;t build intuition, I want to add my ounce of effort to the mix.  It might not solve the original problem, but &lt;em&gt;doing&lt;/em&gt; might get one a lot closer to the solution than &lt;em&gt;talking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;open-standards-and-good-tools&#34;&gt;Open standards and good tools&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A learner should be able to visualise and play with ideas in a tangible way to connect the dots; interesting enough to arouse interest in a subject.  A very good example of this is &lt;a href=&#34;http://explorableexplanations.com/&#34;&gt;Explorable Explanations&lt;/a&gt;.  Content can leverage modern tools to paint a clearer picture and attract beginners too.  These days we see programming books with embedded interpreters for readers to try out the exercise within the comfort of their browsers; physics explanations with playable demos where readers can change parameters to observe corresponding change in a phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such tools are made possible by open technologies like HTML5, JavaScript and SVG, supported by all major browsers.  Atop these, writing a blog is made trivial with many &lt;em&gt;static site generators&lt;/em&gt;, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you create rich material without leaving your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34;&gt;favourite text editor&lt;/a&gt;, for free.  They also do not restrict you to just words like popular blogging platforms; you are free to embed content as rich as games, math equations and vector graphics to express yourself in your own style.  When the idea of starting this site occurred to me, I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://legends2k.github.io/note/hello_hugo&#34;&gt;a demo page&lt;/a&gt; exploring this possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-such-thing-as-a-stupid-question&#34;&gt;No such thing as a stupid question&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a very high probability of errors creeping into the content; worse it might be downright wrong.  &lt;em&gt;If a reader is unable to understand something, I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that it&amp;rsquo;s my ineptitude as a explainer and not the reader&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt;.  It simply establishes the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m primarily a learner and I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with my authoring skills.  In case you notice mistakes, I would really appreciate you pointing it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also motivated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; but that is for a different post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>