<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bits of Insight</title>
    <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bits of Insight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:14:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in the Valley</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/valley_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 10:35:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/valley_review/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved from India to the Silicon Valley; it&amp;rsquo;s almost a year now. Like all humans I developed opinions about my new environment; I want to them record under notes-to-self. Before proceeding, I&amp;rsquo;ll lay down the disclaimer: these are just my views and you&amp;rsquo;re totally entitled to your&amp;rsquo;s. Though I try to be reasonable, absolute logic isn&amp;rsquo;t just impractical but is inapplicable since feelings about one&amp;rsquo;s environment are always rooted in emotions, upbringing, habit, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Inspirers</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:41:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</guid>
      <description>I have been inspired by many unknown personalities all over the internet and otherwise, but a few linger on my mind consistently to be listed here. Not all of them are authors but they work inspired me in some way.
Kalki R. Krishnamurthy A great writer, and freedom fighter, who effortlessly balanced content against gripping narration. He pioneered in writing under a unique genre &amp;mdash; Historical fiction &amp;mdash; by mixing imagination with facts in the right amount and proved that it can be done with great success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello, world</title>
      <link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:36:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Experience I have been writing on StackOverflow for quite a while now. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if these can be called writing since it&amp;rsquo;s purely technical. However, helping newbies with verbose answers has stoked some confidence in me; confidence that I am good at explaining things to people. Additionally, I recently gave an interactive presentation on a math-heavy topic that garnered good reviews; it took 2 months for me to prepare this slide deck viewable on a browser; more than half the time was spent not on technicalities but on the material.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>