<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bookmark on Bits of Insight</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/tags/bookmark/</link><description>Recent content in Bookmark on Bits of Insight</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><copyright>Sundaram Ramaswamy</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 10:52:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://legends2k.github.io/tags/bookmark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Graphics Resouces</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/cg_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:08:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/cg_resources/</guid><description>Here’s a curated list of learning resources I usually recommend for self-studying the domain of Computer Graphics.
Introduction Learning graphics concepts isn’t the same as learning a rendering library; the latter is usually not very beneficial since a new library eventually replaces/takes over. Strive to learn the theory behind the domain, not the tools or their idiosyncrasies. Once you internalize the basic ideas, try doing some CG projects with increasing hardness.</description></item><item><title>Hacker Culture</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/note/hacker_culture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 18:40:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/note/hacker_culture/</guid><description>You can’t learn everything from scratch practically; you need to stand on the shoulder of giants. These articles were very insightful; either it’s a clear writing that shares my already-held belief or something that reshaped my thinking. I’ve collected them over the years. I’ve given short descriptions to most links.
It’s a bookmark page updated once in a while.
By Authors Eric S Raymond Renowned hacker1. He’s written a lot about Unix philosophy including The Art of Unix Programming and The Unix Koans of Master Foo.</description></item><item><title>My Inspirers</title><link>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 22:41:05 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://legends2k.github.io/post/inspirers/</guid><description>I have been inspired by many unknown personalities all over the internet and otherwise, but a few linger on my mind consistently to be listed here. Not all of them are authors but their works inspired me in some way.
Kalki R. Krishnamurthy A great writer, and freedom fighter, who effortlessly balanced content against gripping narration. He pioneered in writing under a unique genre &amp;mdash; Historical Fiction &amp;mdash; by mixing imagination with facts in the right amount and proved that it can be done with great success.</description></item></channel></rss>